engineersgarage.com 2018-12-21

# Privacy Policy of EngineersGarage | EngineersGarage

Dear Visitor,

Please read the privacy policy before using this website.

This Privacy Policy mentions how EngineersGarage collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users of the [https://www.engineersgarage.com](https://www.engineersgarage.com/) (“Site").

EngineersGarage strives to maintain the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all its operations. Any user who finds material posted by another user objectionable is encouraged to contact us via e-mail. EngineersGarage is authorized to remove or modify any data, submitted by any user to its forums, for any reason it feels constitutes a violation of our policies, whether stated, implied or not.

 **1.Personal and Non-Personal identification information**

As the **Data Controller for our Users** ’ data, we may collect **personal and non personal information** of users while visiting the site. 

- **Personal Information** is collected when Users visit our site, register on the site, fill out a form, respond to a survey, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, phone number or professional information. We do not make automated decisions based on the data any User provides.

Users may visit our Site anonymously and refuse to provide information except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities and visiting certain section of the site as they are available only for registered users.

- **Non-personal identification** information which may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

We work hard to protect our site and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold.However, transmission via the Internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarante and shall not be responsible in any form for the security/protection of your information stored with us.

 **2.** **Content**

The content provided on this website is only for the purpose of reference, education and personal use. If you are using our content for reference, you should acknowledge us by putting a link of our website [www.engineersgarage.com](http://www.engineersgarage.com/) under suitable heading. The content should not be used in any form for any commercial purpose without prior permission from us. Although the content posted in EG Labs section is well researched and experimented before posting, however EngineersGarage bears no responsibility in any form for the failures that may arise. EngineersGarage does not bear any responsibility in any form for the content posted by its users. You are solely responsible for checking the accuracy of relevant facts, figures, opinions and comments given on the site. EngineersGarage shall not be responsible in any form for the inaccurate data, information, opinions and comments etc. available on the site in any form.

3 **. Web browser cookies**

We may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly. We use Facebook,Google Analytics to gather and re-target to our audience.

4 **. Use of Information**

We may use information about you for any purposes not inconsistent with our statements under this Privacy Policy or prohibited by applicable law, including to:

-Improve your online experience;

-Connect with you, respond to your comments, questions and requests, provide customer service, and send you informational notices

-Send you newsletters and advertisements and communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards, and events we think may be of interest to you

5 **. Your Data Rights**

Under the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) policies with which we comply, EU Users have eight data rights as follows:

 **-** We will be transparent about how we use your data.

 **-** Users will know exactly how we process their data, as well as what data about them is currently being stored.

 **-** Users can have data rectified if it is incorrect or incomplete.

 **-** Users may have their data deleted if they so choose.

 **-** Users may restrict or completely block the processing of their personal data.

 **-** Users may reuse their personal data for individual use.

 **-** In some instances, Users may object to the use of their personal data.

 **-** Users may object to their use of their data as it relates to automatic processing without human intervention and consequences that have legal bearing on the User.

-We respect your privacy rights and whenever you use our website we ensure that you have reasonable  access to your personal information. If you wish to access or change any personal data we hold about you, or to request that we delete any information about you, you may contact us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section.or mailing us . At your request, we will have any reference to you deleted or blocked in our database.

6 **. How we protect your information**

We take reasonable care for data collection, storage and security to protect against unauthorised access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. However, transmission via the Internet is not completely secure so we cannot guarante and shall not be responsible for the security of your information collected through our Service.

7 **. Sharing your personal information**

We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have not 

opted-out of these services.

8 **. Third party websites, Email Newsletters,Surveys, Design Contests, Webinars & Industry White Papers**

 **-Advertisers**

You may find some advertising or other content while visiting our site that is linked to other sites or services provided by our partners, suppliers, advertisers and third parties. We are not responsible for the content or links that are available on these sites or any unfair practice employed by websites linked to or from our Site

Also, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. All these sites have their own privacy policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

 **-Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising**

We may participate in online advertising networks and exchanges that display relevant advertisements to our visitors, on our site and on Third Party Services based on their interests as reflected in their browsing of the Service and certain Third Party Services. These entities may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to automatically collect information about you and your activities, such as registering a unique identifier for your device and tying that to your online activities on and off of our Service. We may use this information to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on the Service and Third Party Services and better understand your online activity..

 **-Social Media Interaction and third party interaction**

Also, if you use Social Features example “liking”, sharing, or any other feature, and potentially other Third Party Services, information you post or provide access to may be publicly displayed on our site or by the Third Party Service that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a Third Party Service that references our website (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with us in a tweet or status update), your post may be used on or in connection with our Service. Also, both we and the third party may have access to certain information about you and your use of our Service and the Third Party Service. 

 **-Electronic Newsletters:**

If a user has opted-in our data list , they will receive emails about company news, updates, related product or service information, advertisements, etc. The User gives explicit consent to receive the Site’s newsletters by filling out the Site’s registration form, which includes registration for EngineersGarage.com, its forum, and newsletters, as clearly stated on the registration page. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email.

 **-Design Contests, Webinars & Industry White Papers**

If a user registers for Design Contest, Webinar or an Industry white paper, the User acknowledges that their contact information will be shared with the sponsoring company, as stated on the respective registration page.

 **9\. International transfer of data**

We are based out of India and if you are visting the site from outside India, any data that you submit with us may be transferred within India or to other countries where data protection law is not strict. However we will ensure that all the data will be governed under this privacy policy.

 **10\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the rights to makes changes and reissue this privacy policy and any changes will be effective immediately. If you continue using our website /services even after the changes indicates your consent. If you do not agree to the terms under privacy policy you can discontinue using our services.
